Jake Dudum

San Bruno, CA 94066 | Phone: (650) 515-7204 | Email: jakedudum@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jake-dudum-45a967185/

Github: https://github.com/JakeDudum | Portfolio: https://jakedudum.github.io/My-Portfolio/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with CS experience and a life-long passion for solving problems. Highly motivated to learn new technologies and use them to create user-driven applications. Flexible in group environments, able to work on any area of an ongoing project alone or with peers.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End Development, Back-End Development, Database Management, Project Management, Analytical Skills, Debugging, UI/UX

Programming Languages and Frameworks: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, ReactJS, Node.js, Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, jQuery

PROJECTS

Where2P-GitHub: https://github.com/JakeDudum/Where2p | Deployed: https://jakedudum.github.io/Where2p |

A small app that helps users find bathrooms in the nearby area with the ability to add and read reviews as well. My responsibilities for this project were front-end design as well as firebase integration for user reviews. The application uses HTML, CSS, Javascript (AJAX for API calls), jQuery, Materialize, and Firebase.

Bark-GitHub: https://github.com/JakeDudum/Bark | Deployed: https://tranquil-bastion-82369.herokuapp.com/

On bark users can only see blog posts that are in their own area and only post to that area so everything displayed is relevant to where they are. I was personally responsible for the database used for the project (MYSQL with Sequelize) and all calls to the database from front-end to back-end and back-end to database as well as some client-side javascript. This application uses HTML, CSS, Javascript, NodeJS, MYSQL, Heroku(for deployment along with JawsDB), and various node packages for user authentication, time stamps, and running the server.

Jumble-GitHub: https://github.com/JakeDudum/Jumble | Deployed: https://jumble-dash.herokuapp.com/

This is a project management tool suitable for various industries. The site allows users to create projects with names, budgets(with budgets for each department as well), tasks, and problems and display all of the available data in various charts for the user to then modify or complete as need be. For this project I was responsible for the database and all communication to it as well as some front-end react components and charts. The site is a SERN full-stack application(Sequelize, Express, React, Node) that uses charts.js to create charts for all of the data and passport for user authentication.

EXPERIENCE

Zume Inc Mountain View, CA— PielotOctober 2018 - April 2019Amazon Fresh Brisbane, CA— Fresh AssociateApril 2018 - September 2018Progistics San Bruno, CA— Delivery DriverMay 2016 - October 2017Papa John's San Bruno, CA— Delivery DriverDecember 2012 - January 2016

EDUCATION

UC Berkeley Extension San Francisco, CA— Full Stack Web Development Certificate

May 2019 - August

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

University of San Francisco, CA

August 2011 - November 2016

Studied computer science for four semesters and acquired over 24 credits in CS.